Sunilkumar Saini 30/149, Sector-3 Pratap nagar, Jaipur-302033

Contact No.: (M) +91 9028309340 E-Mail: sunilsaini8322@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a challenging role in the area of BDM & Operations Management to contribute towards organizational success with my broad knowledge and expertise.

SYNOPSIS

Ambitious and self-motivated individual with over **8+ years** of experience in quality assurance with focus on providing the recipient with the highest quality services, fully compliant with operations management and finance activities. Deep understanding of technology with focus on delivering business solutions; highly ethical, trustworthy and discreet;

- Team Player with strong problem solving and analytical skills.
- Good decision-making skills with a positive approach.
- Dedicated and highly ambitious to achieve personal goals as well as organizational goals.
- Adroit at learning new concepts quickly, working well under pressure.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Successfully lead projects for development of BOPLAN.
- Successfully lead 5s implementation at plant
- Successfully lead projects on 'Corporate Actions.

WORK HISTORY

SVH Foods Inc.

September 2022 to till date

We are a team of passionate foodies that take care of the Product, the Process and the People.Our Inhouse Brands and other global brands we Represent in Canada. We deliver them to the retailer in the most efficient way to serve end consumer needs.We bring the best products and brands to the consumer. Our nationwide major clientele along with a distribution network helps international brands to reach Canadian consumers. We carefully source products with the consumer and retailer in mind.

Assistant Business Development Manager

Key Deliverables

- Managing daily operations of the orders.
- Ensuring seamless coordination of exports between India and Canada.
- Arrangement and coordination of logistics for both local and international shipments.
- Demonstrated expertise in FIFO, inventory and warehouse management.
- Forecasting, enhancing operational efficiency.
- Led teams to achieve business objectives, optimized workflow procedures.
- Management of vendor relationships.

- Coordinated cross-functional teams to achieve project milestones on schedule and within budget.
- Managed large-scale shipments, resulting in an efficient distribution process.
- Facilitated smooth flow of goods for timely order fulfillment.
- Developed contingency plans to manage unexpected supply chain disruptions.
- Conducted periodic audits, maintaining regulatory compliance.
- Streamlined warehouse operations by implementing efficient inventory management systems.
- Liaised with transport companies for swift delivery of goods.
- Reduced operational costs by negotiating better contracts with suppliers.

Amfico Agencies Pvt. Ltd.

November 2017 to July 2022

Amfico Agencies Pvt. Ltd. is one of the most renowned & diversified companies in the field of bulk liquid logistics & trading. A niche for itself by catering to MNCs & Local Conglomerates across the globe. Prides itself in representing many companies not just across bulk liquid but also across safety solutions. Amfico has spread its wings across Europe, US, Malaysia and China. The goal is to ensure a smooth business entry into the Indian economy as well as facilitate business solutions through representation.

Assistant Business Development Manager Key Deliverables

- Spearheaded product planning and execution for Boplan launch in India,
- Ensuring alignment with customer needs and market demands.
- Developed and managed product lifecycle, meeting prioritized customer requirements.
- Conducted comprehensive market and competitor analysis for Boplan.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure timely delivery and enhanced customer satisfaction.
- Conducted market research to identify emerging trends and opportunities.
- Negotiated contracts with external agencies, securing optimal terms for the company.
- Bolstered customer base through targeted direct email marketing campaigns.
- Identified new customer segments and target audiences, expanding market reach.

TAJ HOTEL (Mumbai)

February 2015 – October 2017

GUEST EXPERIENCE EXECUTIVE

Key Deliverables:

- Collaborate effectively with the team to enhance guest satisfaction &
- To deliver an outstanding guest experience.
- Drive optimum performance to align individual goals with corporate objectives.
- Adhered to safety policies for operational excellence.
- Reported safety issues to enhance workplace security.
- Coordinated team efforts for top guest satisfaction.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Worked effectively in fast-paced environments.

SHERATON MALPENSA HOTEL

July 2011 - December 2015

.

FOOD AND BEVERAGE ASSOCIATE.

Key Deliverables:

- Trained new staff members on company policies and procedures.
- Maintained a clean and organized restaurant to comply with hygiene and health regulations.
- Adhered strictly to established quality standards.
- Responded to customer inquiries and resolved complaints to establish trust and increase satisfaction.
- Maintained effective supply levels by monitoring and reordering food stock and dry goods.

TAJ HOTEL (Mumbai)

February 2008 – January 2011

GUEST EXPERIENCE ASSOCIATE

Key Deliverables:

- Coordinated team efforts for top guest satisfaction.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Worked effectively in fast-paced environments.

SKILLS:

- Client Relationship Management
- Industry Benchmarking
- Brand Development Strategies
- Market Research Evaluation
- Creative Problem-Solving Techniques
- Product Marketing
- Effective Relationship Management
- Networking and Relationship Development
- Effective Task Prioritization

EDUCATION

- **BSc** in Hotel & Tourism Management from YCMOU University.
- Certificate in Customer Loyalty from Sheraton Hotels.
- Certificate of Excellence from Taj Hotels & Palaces.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 20th May, 1984

Languages Known: English, Hindi.

Yours faithfully, Sunilkumar Saini..